[XYLO] I will find you.
Both for me,
and my Knights you doomed.
I’ll find you.
The one who was responsible
for Senerva’s fate.
I'll find you.
And I will kill you.
-[Xylo gasps]
-[TEORITTA] Xylo? Xylo!
Were you walking in the land
of dreams, perchance?
[grunts]
A wisp of a man called Venetim
came calling,
and he requested
that I awaken you.
My work is done.
You may praise me now.
Tell the wisp
I'll be there in a minute.
[TEORITTA] Most unacceptable!
You’ll slip back into a slumber
the moment I depart.
[XYLO] Uh-huh.
For shame!
I commend your honesty,
but your behavior
is worthy of reproach!
Tell me.
Tell you what?
What you’re still doing here.
I assume they told you about me.
[TEORITTA] Uh...
They did.
I know you received
the hero penalty,
reserved for the most
heinous of crimes.
There is more.
They enlightened me
on your past, too.
-So why are you--
-You are my knight!
I know you must have
had a good reason.
[Xylo sighs]
[Xylo scoffs]
[XYLO] My reason is irrelevant.
I murdered a goddess.
That’s the cold, hard truth.
Two events can end a pact.
Either the goddess’s death
or termination
by mutual consent.
-So simply--
-I refuse.
You what?
I chose you.
I shall not sever
our sacred bond.
♪
[Xylo sighs]
[VENETIM] Hey, Xylo,
are you awake yet?
Everything’s a complete mess!
If you don’t stop shouting,
I’m going to rip your head off,
Venetim.
[Venetim chuckles]
[VENETIM] You might
not get the chance.
The way things are going,
I’ll be a goner
before you get
your vindictive hands on me.
Explain.
[VENETIM] We’ve been assigned
our next mission.
[Xylo sighs] Seriously?
[VENETIM] We are
disposable heroes, after all.
Still, I’d very much prefer
not to die,
so could you please
come and help me work out
the details?
Son of a bitch.
[TEORITTA] Take heed, my knight!
We must away.
You are clearly in need
of my divine strength!
-[thudding]
-[gasps]
-[man shouting]
-What’s this disturbance?
[XYLO] Tatsuya and His Majesty.
Pray tell, who might they be?
Well, they're heroes,
just like me.
♪
[Teoritta exclaims]
[TEORITTA] Xylo, this vast river
has turned to ice!
I never would've imagined
one of that size could freeze.
My knight, come to my side
and gaze upon it! Hurry!
-Faster still!
-[sighs]
[TEORITTA] You must
come quickly and look!
[KORMADINO] Your orders.
"The 13th goddess transport
has been suspended.
You are hereby
ordered to clear out
the Zewan Gan Tunnels."
Safe to assume that they have
also been affected
by Demon Blight?
You’re aware of what the
Fourth War of Subjugation did.
The appearance
of Demon Blight Number One,
the Serpent, was catastrophic.
It corrupted our forests,
and even caused the soil
itself to rot.
In the 20 years since
it first arrived,
humanity has lost more than
half of all habitable land.
Whatever the cost,
we must not allow it
to progress any further.
To that end, we have
already deployed
the hero unit to Zewan Gan.
You should be able
to catch up with them
quickly on horseback.
We’ll depart at once.
[KORMADINO]
Then I will leave you to it.
[door lock clicks]
[KORMADINO]
Oh, and one last thing.
Do me a favor,
if you run into
High Priest Marlen,
please give him my regards.
I only wish
I could tell him myself.
♪
Most curious.
I have seen no sign
of that roguish squire
called Dotta.
[VENETIM] 'Cause he’s still
laid up in the repair shop.
[NORGALLE]
I’d wager that’s because
Xylo beat the tar out of him.
Honestly.
As my loyal subjects,
you should be more careful
with the kingdom’s property.
Must've slipped my mind
but I’ll try harder,
Your Majesty.
Pardon, but why do you address
your comrade as a royal?
[XYLO] It’s just easier.
Norgalle is convinced
he’s the king
of the Federated Kingdom,
and it’s no use trying
to persuade him otherwise.
Huh?
[XYLO] He unleashed
a large-scale attack
against his
so-called "usurpers."
That’s why he was sentenced
to be a hero.
He was a terrorist.
[Norgalle grunts]
[TEORITTA] Uh...
And him?
Who precisely is he?
[XYLO] Tatsuya, I don’t know
what his crime was,
but he’s been serving
in the hero unit
longer than any of us.
He seems to be
rather detached from this world.
Every time
a hero is resurrected,
they lose a part of their mind
and their memory.
The same could happen
to the rest of us.
[Teoritta gasps]
[XYLO] Damn it all.
This isn’t justice.
It’s a sentence
far worse than death.
[Venetim panting]
[VENETIM] There, now.
Look at that.
Another warm welcome.
[TEORITTA] Uh...
[XYLO] Let's go.
[TEORITTA] It is as if this town
is under a dismal pall.
[VENETIM]
Can’t really blame them.
They’re on the verge
of being swallowed whole
by the Demon Blight.
[SOLDIER] Your family’s
running out of time.
Please. Is there truly nothing
you can do to help our town?
I am sorry, but the army's
decision is final.
[VENETIM] How unusual.
Normally, everyone
would have been evacuated.
I wonder why
they’re refusing to go.
[Teoritta sighs]
[birds chirping]
-[XYLO] Hey, there, question.
-[WOMAN] Huh?
Are you...
one of those "heroes"?
I swear I’m only here to help.
We came to get
the tunnels under control.
I’m hoping you have some
digging tools we could borrow--
I don’t get it.
Why bother?
We’re doomed.
It's too late for us.
Why didn’t you come sooner?
[door opens, closes]
[Xylo grunts softly]
[GIRL] Pardon?
[XYLO] Hm?
[XYLO] Get lost.
I’m not here to entertain.
[GIRL] The tunnels
are in that direction.
[XYLO] Thank you.
[GIRL] Does this mean
Daddy will come home now?
It’s my birthday, after all.
And he promised me
we’d celebrate together!
[gasps softly]
[Xylo grunts]
Damn it!
She has no business
looking at me like that.
[VENETIM] The Zewan Gan Tunnels
produce high-quality iron
used as a catalyst
in sacred seals.
It seems
Verkle Development Corporation
and the military
poured lots of money into it.
So, it’s pretty ironic that
their precious tunnels wound up
with a bad faerie infestation.
[TEORITTA] How curious.
My knight, tell me more
about these "sacred seals."
If you believe the old men
from the Temple,
they’re a product of the wisdom
bestowed on us by the gods.
As I am now.
There are only two
my body can utilize.
The rest are useless to me.
Tuning sacred seals
is King Norgalle’s specialty.
It may be hard to believe,
but he’s a savant.
He can do things alone
that a whole group
would struggle with.
If you’re curious,
the sacred seal inscribed
on an object
is powered by the light
of the glorious sun.
And a person
must use their life force
and will
to invoke the seal’s might.
They have various effects
to wield.
Such as summoning lightning,
rending the earth below,
or unleashing brutal heat.
[Teoritta exclaiming]
It is exhilarating! Is it not?
At ease. Sacred seals alone
aren’t enough to win.
[VENETIM]
They say it was a month ago
that the miners
turned into faeries
and started attacking
indiscriminately.
[XYLO]
That’s a Demon Blight for you.
[VENETIM] True,
details are fuzzy at best.
We do know the basics.
They’re calling
Number 51, "Lotus."
And we’re on excavation duty.
Our mission is to clear a route
so the Holy Knights
can launch an attack.
By the way,
although it pains me to say it,
as the acting commander here,
I am obligated
to remain in town.
Really?
-Is this some kind of joke?
-[VENETIM] And so...
I beseech you with due haste...
Proceed inside,
and begin your work!
[Xylo sighs]
[cracking]
[Xylo grunts]
[exhales] We’re either
cutting a path through,
or we’re just digging
our own grave here.
[NORGALLE] Come now, I inscribed
those sacred seals myself,
and that’s the best you can do?
I order you to dig faster.
We’re going as fast as we can.
-Right, Tatsu...
-[Tatsuya grunting]
[TEORITTA] Ho-ho-ho!
[TEORITTA] You appear
to be struggling
with the task at hand.
That being said,
are you, at last,
ready to call upon my power?
[XYLO] Hell, no! [grunts]
This work is beneath you.
I won’t waste your stamina.
[TEORITTA] Unacceptable!
I have yet to truly contribute
to this mission!
-Huh?
-How am I to earn your praise
if I am not permitted
to aid in your endeavor?
[XYLO] Just sit down
and shut your mouth.
[Teoritta grunts]
[KIVIA] I’m pleased to see
you’re at least attempting
to do an adequate job.
Hello, Xylo Forbartz.
[Xylo grunts]
Slacking off on a mission
would be a quick way to die.
My Goddess.
If you prefer, you are welcome
to rest with our unit.
I refuse. I wish to continue
observing my knight at work.
-It is my right as a goddess.
-[Xylo grunts]
-Even so--
-She’s spoken.
The goddess has decided
to remain on the front lines
with us.
As sovereign of this realm,
I deem your request denied!
Uh... Say, Xylo,
what ails this man?
Is it perhaps
resurrection madness?
It’s all him.
-[Norgalle grunts]
-[KIVIA] I see.
I was informed that
Dotta Luzulas stole the goddess.
Why didn’t you
explain yourself then?
[chuckles] You never would have
believed me.
And besides,
we didn’t have time to chat.
[KIVIA] Don’t withhold intel
in the future.
When we’re on a mission,
you tell me everything.
[XYLO] Good luck with that.
Why should I bother
when you hand out
these kinds of jobs?
Meaning?
[XYLO] We’re knee-deep
in a faeried mine.
Normally, they’d just
leave the place alone.
Especially since
it’ll be winter before long.
[KIVIA] What are you getting at?
[XYLO] I don’t know
what the military
or Temple folks are thinking,
but on its face,
it’s a pointless mission.
What’s your true aim?
Assuming it’s not just
to torture us
for the sheer fun of it.
Hm... Huh?
Are you planning to use
Teoritta for something?
Answer.
♪
[Kivia scoffs]
Spare me
your conspiracy theories.
Your unit is to carry out
your orders.
Figures.
Infuriating.
Everything about
this damn mission
is fishy as hell.
-[clanging]
-[Xylo grunting]
Huh?
-Stay back!
-[Tatsuya growls]
[Tatsuya yelling]
[grunting]
Where do you think you’re going?
Limiting explosion damage
won't be easy. Tatsuya!
[Tatsuya yelling]
Oh, my. Impressive.
Hmm.
[yelling]
[Tatsuya groaning]
My top soldier.
He’s never failed me. Hm.
He didn’t even need any backup.
But he could probably use
some rest right about now.
[NORGALLE] Oh! Despite the
obvious areas of corruption,
the surface appears safe enough
for our intended usage.
[Norgalle grunts]
And so, this shall serve
as the front-line base
for the Holy Knights.
You may now go ahead
and begin all construction.
-[XYLO] Um... Hm?
-[TEORITTA] Xylo!
It is finally my time. Yes?
Allow me to contribute.
[XYLO] Settle down.
Where shall I plant
this big stake?
There? Huh?
Look, my knight,
the corruption has encroached
even further over yonder!
[Xylo groans] Hold on a minute.
[footsteps]
[TEORITTA] Uh...
[XYLO] Hm.
One every three paces.
That’s how you should
place the stakes.
From here
until that point there.
We’ll tie a rope between them
and make a sacred-seal barrier.
[Teoritta exclaims, chuckles]
Great! It shall be done!
Now, behold!
As I adeptly complete
the assigned task!
Be advised.
I expect ample praise.
[gasps]
-Uh...
-[Xylo sighs]
[XYLO] Just do the best you can.
And try not to hurt yourself.
[TEORITTA]
What is your next task, Xylo?
Getting the supply chests
set out.
All of that has to be in place
before the Holy Knights
-arrive here--
-[thudding]
-[TEORITTA] Huh?
-[XYLO] What's that?
[Norgalle grunts] I daresay,
some of my finest work.
[Teoritta exclaims]
[TEORITTA] Truly magnificent!
What is this lovely item?
[gasps]
A system that greets
unwelcome visitors,
with remorseless slaughter!
I have dubbed it...
-The Zolinvolkov.
-[Teoritta stutters]
You know what it means?
The "judge of fools."
Hmm.
Perfect, but how do the Knights
disarm this thing?
Take a good look
and you will see.
There are parts of the ground
that trigger the attacks,
and other parts
that intentionally do nothing.
But wait, that in itself
is a decoy!
Anyone who is foolish enough
to try to touch the chest
will be scorched by the flames
of judgment!
The only way to disarm it
is with this key I carry--
-[XYLO] Tatsuya!
-What do you think you're doing?
Impudent Fiend!
[XYLO] Are you tryingto get
the whole strike team
killed or what?
Remove everything except
what’s absolutely necessary.
[Norgalle grunts]
[grunting] You rogues!
-One thing is clear.
-[Norgalle shouting]
These hero types
seem to be most eccentric.
[groans] Damn. They’re not gonna
cook through without more heat.
[NORGALLE]
Allow me to fix that.
[gasps]
Do you require
a more powerful flame?
No. That should be good.
[Teoritta grunting]
[Xylo sighs]
[TEORITTA] It is complete!
And even more perfect
than my prior creations!
Shall I make another one
to supplement our meal?
Huh? Go ahead.
Is it not tasty?
I seem to have mastered
the skill known as "cooking"
in no time at all.
Permission granted.
[XYLO] If Dotta
or Venetim were here,
we might have gotten
a little more.
I suspect
they’re not fairly dividing
the military ration budgets.
I’ll have some words
with the Minister of Finance
about this.
That sounds like a plan.
Once the job is over,
you do that.
It would seem
that our mission is going
exceedingly well thus far.
-Is it not?
-[XYLO] Huh?
[TEORITTA] Are we, at last,
in close proximity
to the demon lord?
[Xylo sighs] Most likely.
[Teoritta chuckles]
Our glorious triumphs
would surely
have been impossible
without my blessings.
I have tried my hardest.
Say, do you think
the Holy Knights
will be grateful to me?
Probably, but try not to get
too carried away.
[Teoritta chuckles]
[TEORITTA] My brave knight.
Would you perchance entertain
the notion of defeating
the demon lord by ourselves?
Don’t be stupid.
I have no interest,
and it’s against our orders.
[groans]
Please reconsider my offer!
-You have a goddess with you--
-Hell no!
Join the Holy Knights
if that’s what you want.
[TEORITTA]
Again with this nonsense?
You are my chosen knight.
I exist to bestow
blessings upon you!
It is you.
I need you to tell me
I am a goddess
of superlative power,
or I shall not be satisfied.
-[XYLO] Hmm...
-[chiming]
Xylo, communiqué
from the main force.
Don’t tell me.
Is that a distress signal?
[KIVIA]
Hurry, things are dire.
We need your help.
We’re low on time,
the Demon Blight,
the Knights...
we’re under attack.
[monsters growling]
Incoming! Your orders, Captain?
Prepare to engage!
[roars]
[monsters growling]
All forces, charge!
[growling]
-[Kivia grunts]
-[monsters grunting]
[gasps]
[growls]
[Xylo panting]
[XYLO] It’s even worse
than I expected.
[screaming]
[monster growling]
-We could try--
-[TEORITTA] Wait, my knight.
Those wayward faeries.
Before they transformed,
they were human.
Correct, but now
they’re just knockers.
[growling]
[grunts]
Don’t just stand there, fight!
Even though I hate it,
I know what I’ve gotta do.
If the Holy Knights
get wiped out,
our heads get blown off.
Give the order...
Holy Knight Captain!
[Kivia grunts]
[KIVIA] Xylo Forbartz...
Hurry and flank them!
[Norgalle grunts]
Onward! Go forth and fight,
my elite royal soldiers!
It is our duty
to bring everlasting slumber
to the bewitched subjects
of my kingdom!
[Tatsuya yelling]
[growling]
-It’s our turn.
-Those poor souls.
Tell me, can they not return
to the way they were?
[softly] Huh?
[TEORITTA]
There are people in the city,
who are anxiously awaiting
their safe return.
Once someone has transformed,
there's no going back.
[Xylo grunts] All we can do
is put an end
to their suffering.
This is it! Charge them!
[monsters growling]
[gags]
[KNIGHT 1] That was
a hell of a mission.
[KNIGHT 2] Yeah.
Had no idea humans
could turn into faeries.
[XYLO] What the...
[male miner shivering]
Stop...
-the voice.
-[XYLO] Hey, are you injured?
Hey!
[male miner shivering]
The voice.
It won’t stop.
The voice. It calls...
It would appear
there are a few dozen workers
who didn’t make it
out of the tunnel in time.
That sounds miserable.
[NORGALLE] My loyal subjects.
They have sacrificed everything
in service to my kingdom.
Thus, we must save them
at any cost!
Impossible.
Saving civilians isn’t
one of our mission objectives.
We simply can’t risk losing
more Holy Knights to help them.
[Norgalle gasps]
Tell me something,
purely out of curiosity...
If we were to attempt
a rescue of those civilians,
how many of my knights
do you think I would lose?
[Xylo scoffs]
Guess I’m not the only one
in a tricky position.
I would expect
heavy casualties.
Having to escape
through narrow corridors
while defending civilians
-would be--
-[PRIEST] Captain Kivia,
if I may be so bold,
is it really necessary to ask
the opinion of such a man?
We are to use
scorched-earth seals
to close off the tunnels.
Remember?
Those were Galtuile’s orders.
I’m well-aware.
[NORGALLE]
You intend to abandon them?
My loyal subjects!
This is treason
of the highest degree!
You shall pay.
Your cowardice
is an act of rebellion!
Unhand me!
[chuckles]
A royal embarrassment.
The great Norgalle Senridge,
the last disciple
of Sage Hordeaux,
and the pride of the academy,
reduced to a blathering fool
drowning in madness.
You’re all filthy traitors!
You will be punished,
by order of my royal decree.
[XYLO] Calm down, Your Majesty.
Do what they say or that seal
on your neck will kill you.
Xylo, are you
turning on me as well?
[Xylo sighs]
Uh?
[gasps]
♪
Damn it!
-Stay here. We’ll save them.
-[KIVIA] Uh?
Pardon?
[XYLO] We’ve already set up
the front-line base for you.
The Knights can carry out
the mission as ordered.
If we don't make it out in time,
just bury us alive in there.
Any fatalities will be limited
to heroes.
[priest chuckles]
Such courage!
As expected of my champion!
So may I presume the
Holy Knights are in agreeance?
As soon as we succeed
in our rescue,
you may join them
in lavishing praise upon us--
-[XYLO] Teoritta stays here.
-Huh?
Think about it.
We can’t let a goddess
be buried alive.
Please, it is imperative
that you reconsider.
We must always remain
with each other, my knight--
[RAJIT] Forgive me, Goddess.
[TEORITTA]
Xylo, you have deceived me!
I demand that
you atone for this!
[Xylo grunts]
How can every last one of you
be so damn self-serving?
In all honesty,
I don't give a damn
about the civilians.
Doesn’t matter.
'Cause I'm mad as hell now...
at the commanders
who formed this garbage plan,
and at the people
eagerly awaiting my death.
It’s too late.
I already dug my grave.
Now it’s time to march inside
to the very depths.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
THE PRISON RECORDS OF PENAL HERO
UNIT 9004